Northern Lights of Christmas is a drama, romance, tv
movie film directed by Jonathan Wright.
Zoey Hathaway has been working towards her lifelong goal of being a pilot for years, but everything is thrown off-course
when she unexpectedly inherits a reindeer farm, along with the dangerously handsome ranch hand Alec Wynn.
Now buried in taking care of reindeer and all the Christmas responsibilities, Zoey thinks life has delivered her a
strange and cumbersome blow, and she isn’t sure about Alec, who has his own ideas how best to run things.
Alec, who has never had many people have faith in him, opens up when Zoey invests
trust in him, and the two find themselves falling for each other.
Could they both find happiness in the most unlikely of
circumstances right before Christmas?
Zoey Hathaway, played by Ashley Williams.
Alec Wynn, played by Corey Sevier.
Karen Yazzi, played by Genelle Williams.
Anya Parker, played by Laura Miyata.
Brock Parker, played by Jefferson Brown.
Otto Bismer, played by Art Hindle.
Christmas is an annual festival commemorating the birth of Jesus Christ, observed primarily on December
25 as a religious and cultural celebration among billions of people around the world.
A liturgical feast central to Christianity, Christmas
preparation begins on the First Sunday of Advent.
This is followed by Christmastide, which historically in the West
lasts twelve days and culminates on Twelfth Night.
Christmas Day is a public holiday in many countries and is observed by a majority of Christians; it is also
celebrated culturally by many non-Christians and forms an integral part of the annual holiday season.
The traditional Christmas narrative recounted in the New Testament, known as the Nativity of
Jesus, says that Jesus was born in Bethlehem, in accordance with messianic prophecies.
When Joseph and Mary arrived in the city, the inn had no room, and so they were offered a stable where the Christ
Child was soon born, with angels proclaiming this news to shepherds, who then spread the word.
There are different hypotheses regarding the date of the birth of Jesus.
In the early fourth century, the church fixed the date as December 25,
the date of the winter solstice in the Roman Empire.
It is nine months after Annunciation on March 25, also
the Roman date of the spring equinox.
Most Christians celebrate on December 25 in the Gregorian calendar, which has been adopted
almost universally in the civil calendars used in countries throughout the world.
However, part of the Eastern Christian Churches celebrate Christmas on December 25 of the older
Julian calendar, which currently corresponds to January 7 in the Gregorian calendar.
For Christians, celebrating that God came into the world in the form of man to atone for the
sins of humanity is more important than knowing Jesus Christ's exact birth date.
The customs associated with Christmas in various countries have a mix of
pre-Christian, Christian, and secular themes and origins.
Popular holiday traditions include gift-giving; completing an Advent calendar or Advent wreath; Christmas music and carolling; watching Christmas films; viewing a Nativity play; an exchange of Christmas cards;
attending church services; a special meal; and displaying various Christmas decorations, including Christmas trees, Christmas lights, nativity scenes, poinsettias, garlands, wreaths, mistletoe, and holly.
Additionally, several related and often interchangeable figures, known as Santa Claus, Father Christmas, Saint Nicholas, and Christkind,
are associated with bringing gifts to children during the Christmas season and have their own body of traditions and lore.
Because gift-giving and many other aspects of the Christmas festival involve heightened economic activity,
Christmas has become a significant event and a key sales period for retailers and businesses.
Over the past few centuries, Christmas has had a steadily
growing economic effect in many regions of the world.
The film explores themes of holiday, reindeer, christmas.
The tone is emotional.